Front-end Developer Hyunseok Kim

Bundang-gu, Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do, 13599, Republic of Korea

mobile: 010.8863.2191 e-mail: dragmove@gmail.com github: https://github.com/dragmove

Summary

Versatile Front-end Developer with 13+ years of experience, developing interactive websites and applications in various environments. Specialized in Javascript and subtle motion.

Portfolio

https://dragmove-df96f.firebaseapp.com/

// React, redux, redux-saga, RxJS, styled-component, Express, webpack, etc

Open-source activities

aid.js (https://www.npmjs.com/package/aid.js)

A bundle of Javascript util library to help developers. Most sources were tested by Jasmine. Downloaded more than 35,000 on NPM(Jun 2020).

kihon (https://www.npmjs.com/package/kihon)

A bundle of lite components that provide straightforward interactive UI. Support ES2015+. Downloaded more than 5,000 on NPM(Jun 2020).

Private services

Capture - Webpage Fullscreen Capture

Sep 2016 - current. (https://appsto.re/kr/rxiFeb.i)

iOS Native App to capture the entire webpage on iPhone screen. Designed App, and developed by Swift language. Support English, Japanese, Korean languages for localization. Ranked 70th in the 'productivity' category on the App store Korea(24th May 2018). Downloaded more than 46,300 from the App store(Jun 2020).

Experience

- NCSOFT / Senior Front-end developer

Jul 2014 - Aug 2019

Mainly developed Javascript modules of responsive community websites, simulator applications, internal platform, responsive promotion websites, and UI components with 4 - 10 Front-end Developers.

Markdown editor on Mink messaging App

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019, Mink messenger development department // React, redux, redux-saga, immer, webpack, etc.

Developed Markdown editor based on TUI Editor, and applied to an internal messaging application named Mink. Set up a Unit test environment using Jest. Maintained issues related to Javascript and React components with 4 Front-end Developers.

Game Pre-order responsive websites

May 2019 - Jun 2019, Mobile game web development team // jQuery, RxJS, ScrollMagic, webpack, babel, gulp, etc.

Developed Javascript parts of responsive websites with parallax scrolling effect. Developed various prototype motions for supporting designers. Collaborated with Back-end Developers for OAuth authentication.

- VW / Interactive Director

Dec 2009 - Aug 2012, Interactive department

Developed various Official and Promotion websites (Hyundai E&C, Samsung card, CJ ninebridge, etc) using Flash Actionscript 3.0, Flash Builder 4.x with 1-2 Flash Developers.

- VRICKS REPUBLIC / Senior Interactive Designer

Jul 2007 - Sep 2009, Interactive department

Developed various Flash websites and RIA using Flash Actionscript $2.0\,/\,3.0$ with 2-4 Flash Developers.

Samsung fire RIA for insurance claim

Oct 2008 - Dec 2008, Interactive department

Developed Flash RIA for policyholders claiming insurance money. Collaborated with Back-end Developers working at Samsung fire.

- SALTCAKE / Junior Flash Actionscripter

Mar 2006 - Mar 2007

Developed various Flash websites and GUI applications using Flash Actionscript 2.0(LG Electronics, Motorola, Ritz-Carlton Seoul, etc).

Pantech SKY dialer / SKY IE5 GUI

Jul 2006 - Mar 2007, Design team // Flash Lite 1.1

Developed Flash dialer, GUI on mobile devices with Embedded developers working at Pantech. Achieved the first Flash dialer launched from Pantech.

Awards

&Award 2011 Winner / Web Award Korea 2011, 2010 Grand Prize (3 categories) / Korea Digital Media Award 2010 Grand Prize (2 categories), 2010 Nominee / Web Award Korea 2008 Excellent Prize, Grand Prize, Nominee

Qualification / Certificate

Cambridge English Program High-Advanced Mar 2020, International Language Academy of Canada

JLPT N1 Feb 2006, Japan Foundation

Industrial Engineer Information Processing Jun 2002, Human Resources Development Service of Korea

Education

Kyung Hee University Mar 2000 - Aug 2006, South Korea

Bachelor of Industrial Engineering, College of Techno engineering. Bachelor of Japanese Language, College of Foreign language.